



Satoko Gruson

Bilingual UI/UX Designer I Experience in Project, Cross-functional Team Management and Localization

ABOUT ME

I am a bilingual professional with experience in legal and compliance-related project management within the pharmaceutical and biotech industry. I seek to combine the various skills and experience gained during my professional career with the technical UX/UI knowledge I have developed through training toward a product design and development management career.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- Figma, Adobe Creative (Photoshop. Illustrator, Premier Pro, After Effects and XD)
- Program/Project planning & management
- Cross-functional team management
- Process implementation
- Basic HTML and CSS coding
- Primary and Secondary Research (legal and marketing)
- Translation & localization
- English and Japanese language fluency
- Intermediate level German (TELC Deutsch B2)
- Proficiency in Microsoft Office

CERTIFICATIONS

UI DESIGN PROGRAM

CareerFoundry May 2023

UX ACADEMY FOUNDATIONS

Designlab January 2022

STANFORD CERTIFIED PROJECT MANAGER (S.C.P.M)

Stanford University Jan 2011

MAJOR ACHIEVEMENTS

UI/UX DESIGN

- Training in UI/UX Design fundamentals
 - Visual design fundamentals and UI /UX design principles
 - Competitive analysis, user research and interviews, user persona creation, IA task flows, wireframe, and prototype creation
 - Creation of style guides and responsive web and mobile landing pages using FIGMA
 - Logo creation and animations
 - 4 UI/UX case studies from discovery to delivery
 - Basic HTML and CSS coding

Link to case study: UI Design Case Study

PROGRAM/PROJECT MANAGEMENT

- Successfully rolled out Corporate Compliance programs and projects, which included:
 - Defining the goals and objectives and preparing project charters
 - Managing internal and external stakeholders
 - Strategically guiding project members to ensure timely implementation
 - Leading employee research initiatives to identify needs and concerns to ensure smooth implementation of guidelines and policies through cross-functional teams
 - Continuous Communication and corrective actions as necessary
 - Organizing a company-wide training to ensure program goals were clear to the stakeholders
 - Planning and developing comprehensive and easy-to-learn e-learning programs
 - Regular reporting on progress and management of continuous improvement processes

RESEARCH AND DESIGN

- Conducted primary research on clients through Client Satisfaction surveys to address concerns and possible solutions/ enhancements to financial products
- Secondary Research to evaluate pharmaceutical detailing effectiveness in various regions
- Redesigned intranet site for ease of accessibility to the relevant documentation
- Designed, produced, and supplied new financial services contracts through research of end-user behavior, leading to increased satisfaction levels among dealers

WORK HISTORY

FREELANCER

Caster Biz Co. Ltd.
December 2022 – Present

SENIOR ASSOCIATE COMPLIANCE

Amgen K.K. April 2019- December 2020

SITE CONTRACT LEADER

Paraxel International Inc. November 2018 – March 2019

SENIOR PARALEGAL

Illumina Japan November 2017 – October 2018

LEGAL OPERATIONS

Boehringer Ingelheim Japan Inc. August 2007 - May 2011

MARKETING RESEARCH

Boehringer Ingelheim Japan Inc. November 2004 – July 2007

SALES & MARKETING ANALYST

Primus Financial Services November 2001 - July 2004

DOCUMENTATION & SETTLEMENTS OFFICER

Australia and New Zealand Banking Group Ltd July 2000 - June 2001

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

MASTER OF ARTS IN TRANSLATION & LOCALIZATION MANAGEMENT

Middlebury Institute of International Studies August 2020 – May 2022 GPA 3.97

Major Projects include:

- Design in Internationalization
- Software localization (mainly C#)
- Website creation and translation using WordPress
- DTP translation and editing using Adobe Photoshop/InDesign
- Audio editing and text/subtitle editing using Adobe Audition and Premiere Pro

GRADUATE DIPLOMA OF LAW

BPP Law School September 2008 – November 2010

CERTIFICATE OF INTERNATIONAL LAW

Beasley School of Law at Temple University September 2007 - August 2008

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS/HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT

RMIT University April 1995 - October 1999 - Minor in Marketing